SIMILARSITES EXTENSION PRIVACY POLICY
-------------------------------------

\[Last modified: June 23, 2024\]

This privacy policy (“**Privacy Policy**”) governs the data collection practices of Similarweb Ltd. (“**Company**”, “**we**”, “**us**”) when you install, download and use the SimilarSites browser extension (“**Extension**”) offered on our website, designated landing pages and which are also available through various extension stores, such as Chrome, Mozilla and Edge. The Extension provides a service which allows users to find websites that are similar to the sites they are currently viewing (“**Service**”).

This Privacy Policy contains important disclosures on how we collect, share, and use your personal data or information as further detailed below. To the extent permitted by applicable laws, this Privacy Policy is an integrated part of the binding [Terms of Use](https://www.similarsites.com/termsofuse) (“**Terms of Use**”). Definitions herein shall have the same meaning as defined in the Terms of Use.

PLEASE DO NOT DOWNLOAD, INSTALL, OR ADD THE EXTENSIONS TO YOUR BROWSER, OR USE THE SERVICES IN ANY MANNER BEFORE YOU READ AND ACKNOWLEDGE THIS PRIVACY POLICY. THE USE OF INFORMATION RECEIVED FROM THE GOOGLE API THROUGH THE EXTENSION WILL ADHERE TO THE CHROME WEB STORE USER DATA POLICY INCLUDING THE LIMITED USE REQUIREMENTS THEREIN.

This Privacy Policy applies to all users worldwide. **If you are a resident of California**, please refer to [Section 12. Additional Privacy Information for California Residents](#additional_privacy_information_for_ca_residents) for information about the categories of Personal Information we may collect and your rights under California privacy laws. If you are a resident of Colorado, Connecticut, Virginia, or Utah, please refer to [Section 13. Additional Privacy Information for Certain United States Residents](#additional_privacy_information_for_certain_us_residents), which includes additional information about privacy rights for residents of certain U.S. jurisdictions.

**1\. CONTACT INFORMATION:**

Similarweb Ltd., incorporated under the laws of the state of Israel, is the controller (as such term is defined under the General Data Protection Regulations (“**GDPR**”) or equivalent privacy legislation) of the Personal Data we collect from you. For any question, inquiry or concern related to this Privacy Policy or the processing of your Personal Data, you may contact us by email: [dpo@similarweb.com](mailto:dpo@similarweb.com), or mail at: Similarweb Ltd., ℅ MyEDPO Ltd., Unit 3d North Point House, North Point Business Park, New Mallow Road, Cork, Ireland.

**2\. AMENDMENTS:**

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time and recommend that you check back periodically for the latest version as indicated by the date at the end of the Privacy Policy. Where required by applicable laws, we will provide you with notice of material changes to this Privacy Policy.

**3\. PERSONAL DATA PROCESSED, THE PURPOSE AND LAWFUL BASES:**

We process, collect and share “**Personal Information**” or “**Personal Data**”, as defined under applicable privacy laws, including, without limitations contact information, online identifiers and information that can reasonably identify you (collectively hereinafter “**Personal Data**”). Personal Data does not include non-identifiable information collected or generated via your use of the Extensions and Service that is not linked or linkable to you and could not be used to identify you, whether directly or indirectly with reference to other information (“**Non-Personal Data**”), such as technical information about your browser or device (type of browser, device, language preference, country level location, etc.) and other information that we aggregate or de-identify consistent with applicable law.

We may use and disclose Non-Personal Data related to our business and the Services for quality control, analytics, research, development, and other purposes. Some of this information may be considered “de-identified” under U.S. privacy laws (i.e., data that is no longer linked or reasonably linkable to an identified or identifiable consumer). Where we rely on data that has been “de-identified” as defined by U.S. privacy laws, we will: **(i)** take reasonable measures to ensure that the de-identified information cannot be associated with an individual, household, or device;**(ii)** commit to maintain and use the information in a de-identified form and not attempt to re-identify the information; and **(iii)** contractually obligate any further recipient not to re-identify the de-identified data.

| DATA SET | PURPOSE OF PROCESSING | LAWFUL BASIS (AS DEFINED UNDER GDPR) |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Contact Information:**  <br>When you log in, create an account or otherwise contact us for an inquiry or support, we will collect basic contact information such as email addresses, full names and related general contact information, including login and password information, when you set up an account with us, credentials, username or business email address. | We process the Contact Information for the following purposes:<br><br>* **Authentication**\- to enable you to log in or create an account and to prevent unauthorized access to the Services.<br>    <br>* **Support**\- to provide relevant support when you contact us for troubleshooting or otherwise.<br>    <br>* **General Inquiries**\- to respond to your inquiries about Similarweb or our Services.<br>    <br>* **Security**\- to promote the security of our Services by tracking the use of our Services, enforcing our terms and policies, investigating, and preventing fraudulent, suspicious or illegal activities.<br>    <br>* **Direct Marketing**\- to send you information about our Services and offerings, which we think may be of interest to you.<br>    <br>* **Complying with our legal obligations, including law enforcement requests.** | We process the Contact Information for the purpose of logging in, creating an account and support, under contract necessity and as determined in our [Terms of Use](https://www.similarsites.com/termsofuse).<br><br>Otherwise, we will process the information based on our legitimate interests, provided that our interests are not overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms, for example when responding to your inquiries, for security purposes, to understand, enhance and improve the Services, or otherwise for direct marketing. Where required by applicable law, we will obtain your consent prior to sending you any direct marketing.<br><br>We may also have a legal obligation to collect or otherwise use your Contact Information, for example in order to comply with a law enforcement order or other legal obligations. |
| **Communication Data:**  <br>If and when you contact us, voluntarily, the communication may include Personal Data, such as Contact Information as detailed above. We may collect and maintain a record of your contact details, communications, and our responses.<br><br>We also maintain records of communications and information that you post on our social media channels and information you provide to us related to any customer support requests. | Such information will be used solely to communicate with and support you, and will not be shared with any third parties.<br><br>We collect the Communication Data to respond to your inquiries.<br><br>We may use the information for improving and enhancing the Services, promoting the security of our Services, enforcing our terms and policies, investigating, and preventing fraudulent, suspicious or illegal activities, preventing unauthorized access to the Services, complying with judicial proceedings, court orders or legal processes or to respond to lawful requests. | We process your information under contract necessity and as determined in our [Terms of Use](https://www.similarsites.com/termsofuse) for support services.<br><br>Otherwise, we will process the information based on our legitimate interests that are not overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms, for example when responding to your inquiry, when necessary for security purposes, to understand, enhance and improve the Services.<br><br>We may also have a legal obligation to collect or otherwise use your Contact Information, for example in order to comply with a law enforcement order under our legal obligations. |
| **Online Identifiers:**  <br>We may process Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, which are trimmed and hashed (irreversibly encrypted) on a daily basis, and thus are not and cannot be traced back to an individual or used in any way to identify an individual, globally unique identification number, which is a random number we generate to keep track of the data sets we collect and if required, enable us to execute your data rights requests as further detailed below (“**GUID**”), user agent, device ID, etc. | Online Identifiers may be used to promote the security of our Services by tracking the use of our Services to detect abnormal user behaviour, for enforcing our terms and policies, investigating, and preventing fraudulent, suspicious or illegal activities, and preventing unauthorized access to the Services.<br><br>This information may also be used to improve and enhance the Services. | We process such information on the basis of our legitimate interests to ensure the security of our Services. We have conducted our assessments to ensure that our processing is reasonable and that our interests are not overridden by your interests, fundamental rights or freedoms. |
| **Usage Data:**  <br>When you use our Services we will collect certain telemetry data regarding your interaction with the Services, time spent, features used, logs (i.e., time of access and duration of use), crashes, and analytic data | We collect your information for the purpose of providing and improving the Services. This information helps us monitor the security and performance of our Services, understand how the Services are used, optimize user engagement and customize and enhance your experience. | Usage Data is processed based on our legitimate interests that are not overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. |
| **Browsing and Activity Data:**  <br><br>This data includes URL referrer, URLs viewed or visited, pages ads viewed or clicked, ad URL, search engine results page data (keyword, order or index of results, links of results, title, description, and ads displayed).<br><br>We make sure that the Browsing Data is cleaned and scrubbed either on your device (i.e., on the client side) prior to being sent to our servers or following its collection (i.e., on the server side), for the purpose of removing and filtering any information that could be used to identify you or another individual. | We use Browsing and Activity Data to provide the Services. This means that we need this information in order to provide in-depth analysis of traffic and engagement metrics about pages you are browsing and visiting.<br><br>We also use and disclose the Browsing and Activity Data for market intelligence or analytics purposes. | For the purpose of providing the Services as set forth in the [Terms of Use](https://www.similarsites.com/termsofuse), the Browsing and Activity Data is processed for contract necessity.<br><br>Otherwise, the secondary use of the de-identified, filtered, anonymized and aggregated Browsing and Activity Data, is carried out based on your consent, where such consent is required by applicable laws. You can withdraw your consent at any time as detailed below through the opt-out options. You can opt-out of the collection of the Browsing Data by following the instructions in the “Opt Out Right” section below |
| **AI Inputs and Outputs:**  <br><br>This information includes prompts, queries, content, and other inputs that you may enter or submit to certain artificial intelligence (AI) tools, and results or other outputs that you may receive from such AI tools. We are only interested in the input and output terms or results of your interaction with these AI tools.<br><br>Considering the nature and general scope of input and output that is typical to AI tools, some sensitive personal data may be inadvertently processed in the provision of our Services. However, the aim of the processing is not the collection of any Personal Data or data that could identify you. While we cannot guarantee that all Personal Data is removed, we do take steps to remove or filter out identifiers and Personal Data that you may enter or submit to these AI tools. | We use the AI Inputs and Outputs to provide the Services. This means that in order to provide the in-depth analysis of traffic and engagement metrics that you expect by using the Service, we need to understand how you interact with AI tools. | For the purpose of providing the Service as set forth in the [Terms of Use](https://www.similarsites.com/termsofuse), the AI Inputs and Outputs are processed for contract necessity.<br><br>Otherwise, the secondary use of the de-identified, filtered, anonymized and aggregated AI Inputs and Outputs, is carried out based on your consent, where such consent is required by applicable laws. To the extent sensitive personal data is inadvertently processed, such data will be processed on the basis of your explicit consent, where required by applicable law. You can withdraw your consent at any time as detailed below through the opt-out options. You can opt-out of the collection of the AI Inputs and Outputs by following the instructions in the “Opt Out Right” section below |
| **Identity and Access Management Services (SAML/OAuth/SSO):**  <br>We may collect information about what third-party (OAuth) accounts (e.g., Google sign-in, GitHub, Facebook) and identity and access management services (e.g., Okta) (each an “IAM Service”) that you use, including which applications or services you access or authenticate via your use of IAM Services. However, we do not collect your username or credentials or store any authentication tokens related to these IAM Services. | We use this information in order to provide the Services. This means that we need this information in order to provide in-depth analysis of engagement metrics with respect to the use of these IAM Services and the applications and other services that you access via the IAM Services.<br><br>We also use and disclose this information for market intelligence or analytics purposes. | For the purpose of providing the Services as set forth in the [Terms of Use](https://www.similarsites.com/termsofuse), this information is processed for contract necessity.<br><br>Otherwise, the secondary use of this information in a de-identified, filtered, anonymized and aggregated form, is carried out based on your consent, where such consent is required by applicable laws. You can withdraw your consent at any time as detailed below through the opt-out options. You can opt-out of the collection of this information by following the instructions in the “Opt Out Right” section below |

We may share some of the data sets listed in the table above if we have a legal obligation to do so and we may compile and disclose analytics and market intelligence data derived from the data we collect about you and other users through the Services. Generally, the data that we disclose to customers is aggregated and converted into metrics that do not identify you. In limited cases, we may disclose your Personal Data to our clients so that they may conduct their own analysis on consumer behaviours; however, we contractually prohibit them from using this data in order to reach you with targeted advertising or from further sharing or disclosing this data to third parties.

**4\. HOW WE COLLECT PERSONAL DATA**

* **Directly from you:** Personal Data provided voluntarily by you, when you provide it to us by reaching out or signing in.
    
* **Automatically while using the Extension or Services:** Personal Data collected automatically or inferred about you while using the Service such as Usage Data or Online Identifiers.

**5\. COOKIES AND SIMILAR TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES**

We may use cookies, or other similar tracking technologies (“**Cookies**”) to gather, store, and track certain information related to your access and interaction with our Extension. Cookies are very helpful and may be used for a variety of different purposes. These purposes for which we use Cookies include (without limitation), allowing you to navigate between pages more efficiently, enabling the automatic activation of certain features, remembering your preferences and making the interaction between you and our Services quicker and easier, to secure, prevent fraud and protect our Services.

These Cookies enable core functionality of the service. You may disable these by changing your browser settings, but that will affect how the Services function.

Please visit: [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.similarsites.com/www.allaboutcookies.org) to learn more about cookies.

**6\. HOW IS THE DATA SHARED?**

We may disclose Personal Data to the following parties for the following purposes:

* **Vendors and Service Providers.** We may share Personal Data we collect with our service providers, processors, and vendors who perform functions on our behalf to allow us to provide the Services (for example: cloud hosting providers, payment processors, etc.).
    
* **Business Partners.** We may also share certain Personal Data as necessary prior to the completion of a transaction or corporate transactions such as financings or restructurings, merger, acquisition transaction, to lenders, auditors, and third-party advisors, including attorneys and consultants, as part of due diligence or as necessary to plan for a transaction.
    
* As otherwise described in Section 3 (Personal Data Processed, The Purpose and Law Bases) above.
    
* **Others, as permitted or required by applicable law.** We may disclose Personal Data to third parties (authorities, legal representatives, regulators, government entities, and law enforcement) to the extent permitted or required by applicable laws. It may also include certain disclosures that we are required to make. We may disclose your Personal Data when we believe it is appropriate to do so to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Use, or as evidence in litigation in which we are involved.

**7\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**

Transfers of your Personal Data will be made in accordance with applicable laws. We will take the necessary steps to ensure that international transfers of Personal Data meet all requirements under applicable data protection laws. When Personal Data is transferred outside the country where it was originally collected, we will take the steps necessary (and to the extent required by applicable laws) to ensure that sufficient safeguards are provided to such data during its transfer and processing. Some of the measures implemented to safeguard your Personal Data include ensuring that the recipient is bound by specific contractual clauses approved by relevant data protection authorities to provide adequate protection for Personal Data. Where applicable, you can request a copy of the relevant contractual safeguards that we have put in place.

**8\. DATA RETENTION POLICY**

Unless you instruct us otherwise, we retain the information we collect for as long as needed to provide the Services and to comply with our legal obligations. We believe in data minimization and only keep the information we truly need and only for the period of time required.

**9\. HOW DO WE SAFEGUARD YOUR INFORMATION?**

We endeavour to use security methods and encryption when handling data (i.e., we handle the user data securely, including by transmitting it via modern cryptography). We have implemented and maintain appropriate technical and organisational security measures, policies and procedures designed to reduce the risk of accidental destruction or loss, or the unlawful or unauthorised destruction, loss, alteration, disclosure or access to your Personal Data. However, we cannot guarantee the security of information transmitted through the internet. As the security of information depends in part on the security of the computer you use to communicate with us and the security you use to protect your user IDs and passwords, please take appropriate measures to protect this information.

Please contact us at: [dpo@similarweb.com](mailto:dpo@similarweb.com), if you feel that your privacy was not dealt with properly, in a way that was in breach of our Privacy Policy, or if you become aware of a third party’s attempt to gain unauthorised access to any of your Personal Data. We will make a reasonable effort to notify you and the appropriate authorities (if required by applicable law) in the event that we discover a security incident related to your Personal Data.

**10\. Privacy Choices**

Our goal is to be clear about what information we collect so that you can make meaningful choices about how it is used. We allow you to exercise certain choices and controls in connection with your information. Depending on your relationship with us, your jurisdiction and the data protection laws that apply to you, you may have certain rights with respect to your personal information.

In the table below you can review your choices depending on your interaction with us, how you can exercise them, and appeal a decision we take in this regard. Any specification per geo-location or territory are available below the table:

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| RIGHT TO BE INFORMED, RIGHT TO KNOW | You have the right to confirm whether we collect Personal Data about you, and additional information about how we use and share your data. Some of this information is contained in this Privacy Policy. |
| ACCESS RIGHTS | You further have the right to know which Personal Data we specifically hold about you, and receive a copy of such or access it, if you wish to exercise this right, please contact our Data Protection Officer at: [dpo@similarweb.com](mailto:dpo@similarweb.com). |
| RIGHT TO CORRECTION | You have the right to correct inaccuracies in your Personal Data, taking into account the nature and purposes of each processing activity. If you wish to exercise this right, please contact our Data Protection Officer at: [dpo@similarweb.com](mailto:dpo@similarweb.com). |
| RIGHT TO RESTRICTION | In certain circumstances, you have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your Personal Data. If you wish to exercise this right, please contact our Data Protection Officer at: [dpo@similarweb.com](mailto:dpo@similarweb.com). |
| RIGHT TO BE FORGOTTEN, RIGHT TO DELETION | In certain circumstances, you have the right to request the deletion of the Personal Data we hold about you. If you wish to exercise this right, please contact our Data Protection Officer at: [dpo@similarweb.com](mailto:dpo@similarweb.com). |
| RIGHT TO DATA PORTABILITY | You have the right to obtain your Personal Data in a structured and machine readable format that allows you to transmit the data to another entity without hindrance. We will select the format in which we provide your copy. If you wish to exercise this right, please contact our Data Protection Officer at: [dpo@similarweb.com](mailto:dpo@similarweb.com). |
| RIGHT TO OBJECT TO PROCESSING BASED ON OUR LEGITIMATE INTERESTS | You can object to any processing of your Personal Data which has our legitimate interests as its lawful basis. Where you exercise this right, we will have an opportunity to demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate interests which override your rights and freedoms. If you wish to exercise this right, please contact our Data Protection Officer at: [dpo@similarweb.com](mailto:dpo@similarweb.com). |
| RIGHT TO WITHDRAW CONSENT UNDER THE EU AND UK LAWS, AND IN THE US THE RIGHT TO OPT OUT FROM: (I) SELLING PERSONAL DATA; (II) RIGHT TO OPT OUT FROM TARGETED ADVERTISING; AND (III) RIGHT TO OPT OUT FROM PROFILING AND AUTOMATED DECISION MAKING | **Browsing Data:** You can withdraw your consent and stop the automated collection and sharing of your Personal Data for which your consent was required, by opting out of the data collection through the extension settings, clicking on the “Your Privacy Choices“ link and turning off the automated collection of the relevant Personal Data. Please note that once you opt out or turn off the permissions, some or all of the Services will no longer be available. Please note that your withdrawal of consent will not affect any of the processing we have carried out, prior to the exercise of this right.<br><br>**Sale of Personal Data/Targeted Advertising/ Profiling:** If and to the extent applicable, you have the right to opt out of the sale of your Personal Data. **We do not process Personal Data for the purpose of targeted advertising or profiling and automated decision making. We further do not use any Personal Data for automated decision making.**<br><br>Last, you are able to install privacy-controls in the browser’s settings to automatically signal the opt-out preference to all websites you visit (such as the Global Privacy Control). |
| RIGHT TO A COPY OF THE SAFEGUARDS FOR INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS | Where applicable, you can request a copy of or reference to the safeguards under which your Personal Data is transferred outside location. |
| RIGHT TO APPEAL OR COMPLAINT | If we decline to take action on your request, we shall inform you without undue delay as required under applicable laws. The notification will include a justification for declining to take action and instructions on how you may appeal, if applicable. Depending on your location, you may also have the right to lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority. |
| NON-DISCRIMINATION | Where granted by applicable laws, you may have the right to not be discriminated against. Such discrimination may include denying a good or service, providing a different level or quality of service, or charging different prices. We do not discriminate against our users. If you feel that we have discriminated against you, please contact us through our Data Protection Officer at: [dpo@similarweb.com](mailto:dpo@similarweb.com). |

We will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes and will make every reasonable effort to respect your wish to exercise your rights as quickly as possible and in any event, within the timescales provided by data protection laws.

**11\. MINORS**

Children under 18 (or any younger age, to the extent required under applicable laws) are prohibited from using the Service. In the event that we become aware that a user who is considered a child under applicable laws, has shared any information, we will discard such information. If you have any reason to believe that a child has shared any information with us, please contact our Data Protection Officer at: [dpo@similarweb.com](mailto:dpo@similarweb.com).

**12\. ADDITIONAL PRIVACY INFORMATION FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS**

In this section, we provide information for California residents, as required under California privacy laws, including the California Consumer Privacy Act, as amended (“**CCPA**”), which requires that we provide California residents certain specific information about our information practices, including how we process their Personal Information, whether collected online or offline. Under the CCPA, “**Personal Information**” is any information that identifies, relates to, describes, is reasonably capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular California resident or household. This section of the Privacy Policy does not apply to publicly available information or Personal Information that is otherwise exempt under the CCPA. To the extent you are a resident of California, and we collect “Personal Information” subject to CCPA, the following applies.

**Categories of Personal Information Collected and Disclosed:**

While our processing of Personal Information varies based upon our relationship and interactions with you, the table below identifies the categories of Personal Information we may collect about you (and may have collected in the prior 12 months), as defined by the CCPA, as well as the categories of third parties to whom we disclosed Personal Information for a business purpose.

| Categories of Personal Information Collected | Third Party Disclosures for Business or Commercial Purposes |
| --- | --- |
| **Identifiers**. Includes direct identifiers, such as name, alias, account number or unique personal identifier; email address, phone number, and other contact information; IP address and other online identifiers. | * Advisors and agents<br>* Security and fraud prevention providers<br>* Business customers<br>* Others as required by law |
| **Customer Records**. Includes information such as name, user ID, account name, contact information, and other similar information. For example, this may include information collected when an individual purchases our Services or enters into an agreement with us related to our Services. | * Advisors and agents<br>* Security and fraud prevention providers<br>* Regulators, government entities and law enforcement<br>* Others as required by law |
| **Commercial Information**. Includes records of products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or use histories or tendencies. | * Advisors and agents<br>* Business customers<br>* Security and fraud prevention providers<br>* Regulators, government entities and law enforcement<br>* Others as required by law |
| **Internet or Other Electronic Network Activity Information**. Includes but is not limited to, browsing history, clickstream data, search history, and information regarding interactions with our website and services, advertisements, including other usage data related to your use of any of our services or other similar online services. | * Advisors and agents<br>* Security and fraud prevention providers<br>* Business customers<br>* Others as required by law |
| **Profiles and Inferences**. Such as inferences drawn from any of the information described in this section about a consumer including inferences reflecting the consumer’s preferences, characteristics, behaviours, attitudes, abilities, and aptitudes. | * Affiliates and subsidiaries<br>* Regulators, government entities and law enforcement<br>* Others as required by law |
| **Sensitive Personal Information**. In some circumstances, since we generally collect information on all the URLs visited these may include URLs or visits to sensitive websites. Such sensitive websites may relate to religious or philosophical beliefs, consumer health related data, and information concerning a consumer’s sex life or sexual orientation. | * Business customers |

**Sources of Personal Information:**

We generally collect Personal Information from the following categories of sources: directly or indirectly from you; third parties; automatically, including personal information derived/inferred about users based upon their browsing or other data; and operations systems and platforms; business partners; vendors and service providers; publicly available sources; Internet service providers.

**Collection, Use, and Disclosure:**

* Operating Services and providing related support
    
* Analytics and improvement
    
* Communication
    
* Marketing, advertising, and campaign management
    
* Insight development and data enhancement
    
* Security and protection
    
* Business transfers
    
* Market intelligence or analytics services of our affiliates
    
* Compliance and legal process
    
* Auditing, reporting, and other internal operations
    
* Provision of Services by us and by our service providers, processors, and vendors
    
* General business and operational support

**Sales and Sharing of Personal Information:**

The CCPA defines “sale” as disclosing or making available Personal Information to a third-party in exchange for monetary or other valuable consideration, and “sharing” includes disclosing or making available Personal Information to a third-party for purposes of cross-context behavioural advertising. We may “sell” or “share” the following categories of Personal Information: Identifiers, commercial information, internet and electronic network activity information, profiles and inferences, and sensitive personal information, as described above. We may “sell” or “share” these categories to business customers so that our business customers may better understand consumer behaviour and analyze and improve their marketing and advertising campaigns.

We do not sell or share personal information about individuals who we know are under age sixteen (16).

**Data Retention:**

We retain the Personal Information we collect only as reasonably necessary for the purposes described above or as otherwise disclosed to you at the time of collection. When deciding how long to keep your Personal Information, we consider whether we are subject to any legal obligations (e.g., any laws that require us to keep records for a certain period before we can delete them) or whether we have taken any legal positions (e.g., issued any legal holds or otherwise need to preserve the information). Rather than delete your data, we may also de-identify it by removing identifying details. Where we have committed to maintaining and using Personal Information in a de-identified form, we agree not to re-identify deidentified data except as permitted by applicable law.

**Your CCPA Rights:**

The CCPA provides California residents with specific rights regarding Personal Information. Subject to certain conditions and exceptions, California residents have the following rights with respect to their Personal Information:

* **Right to Know** You have the right to request: (i) the categories or. Personal Information we collected about you; (ii) the categories of sources from which the Personal Information is collected; (iii) our business or commercial purposes for collecting, selling, or Personal Information; (iv) the categories of third parties to whom we have disclosed Personal Information; and (v) a copy of the specific pieces of Personal Information we have collected about you.
    
* **Right to Delete**. You have the right to request we delete Personal Information we have collected from you.
    
* **Right to Correct**. You have the right to request that we correct inaccuracies in your Personal Information.
    
* **Right to Opt-Out of Sales and Sharing**. You have the right to opt-out of “sales” and “sharing” of your Personal Information, as those terms are defined under the CCPA.
    
* **Right to Limit Use**. You have the right to limit use and disclosure of your sensitive personal information.
    
* **Right to Non-Discrimination**. You have the right not to be subjected to discriminatory treatment for exercising any of the rights described in this section.

**Exercising Your Privacy Rights:**

California residents may exercise their CCPA privacy rights as set forth below:

* **Right to Know, Delete, Correct, and Limit**. California residents may submit CCPA requests to access/know, delete, and correct their Personal Information, and limit the use/disclosure of their Sensitive Personal Information by emailing us at [privacy@similarweb.com](mailto:privacy@similarweb.com).
    
    When you submit a request, we will take steps to verify your identity and request by matching the information provided by you with the information we have in our records. In some cases, we may request additional information in order to verify your identity, or where necessary to process your request. If we are unable to verify your identity after a good faith attempt, we may deny the request and, if so, will explain the basis for the denial.
    
    You may also designate someone as an authorized agent to submit requests and act on your behalf. Authorized agents will be required to provide proof of their authorization in their first communication with us, and we may also require that the relevant consumer directly verify their identity and the authority of the authorized agent.
    
* **Right to Opt-Out of Sales and Sharing**. To exercise your right to opt-out of the “sale” or “sharing” of your Personal Information, you may do so by clicking the “Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information” link on the footer of our website and by submitting a request to opt-out of the selling or sharing of your Personal Information via our [Do not Sell or Share My Personal Information form](https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfHW2dtf4YAYei3QnYO_lq_9S2GdN6PGVXrWsWhRTdS9F2XIQ/viewform). You can also email us directly at: [dpo@similarweb.com](mailto:dpo@similarweb.com) to submit an opt-out request. We will fulfil your opt out request based upon the Personal Information in our records that is linked or reasonably linkable to the information provided in your request.

**13\. ADDITIONAL PRIVACY INFORMATION FOR CERTAIN UNITED STATES RESIDENTS**

Residents of certain U.S. states, including Colorado, Connecticut, Virginia, and Utah, may have additional rights under applicable privacy laws and be entitled to additional disclosures.

**Sale of Personal Data:**

We may sell the following categories of Personal Data: Identifiers, commercial information, internet and electronic network activity information, profiles and inferences, and “sensitive data”, as that term is defined under applicable U.S. privacy laws. We sell such categories of Personal Data to our business customers so that they may conduct their own analysis on consumer behaviours and analyze and improve their marketing and advertising campaigns.

**Consumer Rights:**

Residents of certain U.S. states, including Colorado, Connecticut, Virginia, Washington, Nevada and Utah, may have additional rights under applicable privacy laws, subject to certain limitations, which may include:

* **Access**. The right to confirm whether we are processing their Personal Information and to obtain a copy of their Personal Information in a portable and, to the extent technically feasible, readily usable format.
    
* **Delete**. The right to delete their Personal Information provided to or obtained by us.
    
* **Correct**. The right to correct inaccuracies in their Personal Information, taking into account the nature and purposes of the processing of the personal information.
    
* **Opt-Out**. To opt out of certain types of processing, including: (i) to opt out of the “sale” of their Personal Information; (ii) to opt out of targeted advertising by us; and (iii) to opt out of any processing of Personal Information for purposes of making decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects.

You may submit a request by emailing us as [privacy@similarweb.com](mailto:privacy@similarweb.com). When you submit a request, we will take steps to verify your identity and your request by matching the information provided by you with the information we have in our records. In some cases, we may request additional information in order to verify your identity, or where necessary to process your request. If we are unable to verify your identity after a good faith attempt, we may deny the request and, if so, will explain the basis for denial and how to remedy any deficiencies, where applicable.

To opt out of sales by us, you can either email us at [privacy@similarweb.com](mailto:privacy@similarweb.com) or submit a request to opt out of the selling of your Personal Information via our [Do not Sell or Share My Personal Information form](https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfHW2dtf4YAYei3QnYO_lq_9S2GdN6PGVXrWsWhRTdS9F2XIQ/viewform).

Authorized agents may initiate a request on behalf of another individual by contacting us at [privacy@similarweb.com](mailto:privacy@similarweb.com); authorized agents will be required to provide proof of their authorization and we may also require that the relevant consumer directly verify their identity and the authority of the authorized agent.
